<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="relnotes.xsl"?>
<release_notes>

<release>
    <title>Contexo 1.0 beta</title>
    <version>1.0b</version>
    <date>2007-10-25</date>

    <comments>
        <entry></entry>
    </comments>
    
    <changes>
        <add>Added support for commandfiles for library packers (ARCOM field in CDEF). See userguide for info. (solves problem with long commandlines)</add>
        <add>Added error check if unknown character encoding schemes are specified in BC format.</add>
        <add>Added specific compiler definition for VC 6 with prepdefine SCB_NO_64INT added to CCCOM and CXXCOM.</add>
        <add>Added documentation about which preprocessor symbols that are added when using DEBUG_BUILD or DEBUGMODE_MEMORY in BC format.</add>
        <add>Added assertion function for code module verification.</add>
        <add>Added warning if headers can't be located by dependency manager.</add>
        <add>Added userguide reference documentation of CDEF format.</add>
        <mod>'--verb' option added to commandline syntax documentation.</mod>
        <mod>Removed obsolete compiler definition msvc7.cdef.</mod>
        <mod>Changed priority of xdepends variable definitions. System config goes first and user is warned about overrides.</mod>
        <mod>User contexo dir created automatically if not present.</mod>
        <mod>Constrained all usage info texts to 80 column boundary.</mod>
        <mod>Added commandfile token to all msvc configs.</mod>
        <mod></mod>

        <bugfix>Fixed issues with arm_symbian compiler definition.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Logfile written to output path instead of working directory.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Fixed bug in #include parser which caused commented out include statements to persist.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>comp2vcproj and mod2vcproj modified to add external dependencies to include paths of project</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Problem solved with library packers failing due to long commandlines (fixed by added commandfie feature).</bugfix>

    </changes>
    
    <known_issues>
        <entry>Dependency manager currently is unable to detect changes in dependency structures when a code module have external dependencies (using xdepends file). Thus all code modules having external dependencies are currently always rebuilt unconditionally.</entry>
        <entry>Compiler options declared in buildlog only includes those specified in the BC field "CFLAGS", erronously excluding flags from the cdef field "CCCOM" etc.</entry>
        <entry>Debug info is currently not generated incrementally for msvc builds. Any pdb file will currently alwasy reflect only the code module built most recently.</entry>
        <entry>Still no linker support.</entry>
        <entry>Userguide and python API reference lacking information on some areas of the system.</entry>
    </known_issues>

</release>


<release>
    <title>Contexo 0.92 beta</title>
    <version>0.92b</version>
    <date>2007-05-25</date>

    <comments>
        <entry>IMPORTANT: Contexo now requires Python version 2.4 or newer. Version 2.3 is no longer supported
        due to usage of Python 'set' objects. Furthermore it is required to uninstall previous
        versions of the build system du to changes in system structure and introduction of new install syste.</entry>

        <entry>This release introduces major feature updates and bugfixes. The system structure has been
        somewhat altered and a new install system is used for windows, thus a full uninstall of previous
        versions is highly recommended.</entry>
    </comments>
    
    <changes>
        <add multiline="1">
            <row>Dependency and synchronization manager module implemented. Adding the following top level features:</row>
            <row/>
            <row>- Dynamic resolution of dependencies between Contexo code modules. 'depends' files now obsolete.</row>
            <row>- Source files rebuilt only when changed since last build.</row>
            <row/>
        </add>
        <add>Added commandline tool mod2vcproj.py.</add>
        <add>Added commandline tool comp2vcproj.py.</add>
        <add>Verbose option ('--verb') added to buildcomp.py and buildmod.py.</add>
        <add>'--sl' option added to buildmod.py with same function as in buildcomp.py.</add>
        <add>Build duration displayed by buildmod.py and buildcomp.py.</add>
        <add>New CDEF option ECHO_SOURCES added which outputs names of source files built.</add>
        <add>New CDEF option ARCOM_METHOD added which specifies if the AR commandline creates/appends or creates/replaces object files</add>
        <add>Warning displayed when unknown CDEF options are encountered.</add>
        <add>Added compiler definition for wince (msvc_wince.cdef).</add>
        <add>Added compiler definition for RealView 2.2 thumb mode (rvct2x_tcc.cdef).</add>

        <mod>Install system changed to Nullsoft Install System (NSIS).</mod>
        <mod>_UNICODE and UNICODE added as preprocessor symbols when building for UTF16.</mod>
        <mod>More comprehensive trace output of switched environment on higher verbose levels.</mod>
        <mod>First option of all commandline tools is explicit and may be omitted.</mod>
        <mod>Codewarrior 2.8 compiler definition updated with gcc style include policy.</mod>
        <mod>Current directory always searched first for a code module location.</mod>
        <mod>File extensions of BC and COMP files passed on the commandline are now optional.</mod>
        <mod>Warning level 4 in all standard msvc build configs (/W4). Warnings as errors (/WX) temporarily suspended.</mod>
        <mod>Added Python version check and automated selection of OS components for install_pymods.py.</mod>
        <mod>%TARGET variable no longer mandatory in commandline mask.</mod>

        <bugfix>Error in environment switch solved which prevented correct switching. (Also resolves known issue in previous release regarding environment switch on Linux).</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Numerous bugs fixed in the system's standard compiler definitions.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>switchcfg.py now rejects non-existant config files.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>'xdepends' variables now handles multiple paths separated with semi colon.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Fixed error when '--sh' was used with buildmod.py</bugfix>

    </changes>
    
    <known_issues>
        <entry>Dependency manager currently is unable to detect changes in dependency structures when a code module have external dependencies (using xdepends file). Thus all code modules having external dependencies are currently always rebuilt unconditionally.</entry>
        <entry>Compiler options declared in buildlog only includes those specified in the BC field "CFLAGS", erronously excluding flags from the cdef field "CCCOM" etc.</entry>
        <entry>Logfile currently not exported to output directory.</entry>
        <entry>Debug info is currently not generated incrementally for msvc builds. Any pdb file will currently alwasy reflect only the code module built most recently.</entry>
        <entry>Still no linker support.</entry>
        <entry>Userguide and python API reference lacking information on some areas of the system.</entry>
        <entry>CDEF format still lacking any documentation due to still being under design/construction.</entry>
    </known_issues>

</release>


<release>
    <title>Contexo 0.91 beta</title>
    <version>0.91b</version>
    <date>2007-02-13</date>

    <comments>
        <entry>This release contains bugfixes and commonly requested features after initial release.</entry>
    </comments>
    
    <changes>
        <add>Added commandline tool 'expmodif.py' which provides functionality for exporting public headers (the interface) from code modules.</add>
        <add>Added support for defining 'xdepends' variables in system config file. (treated secondary by system)</add>
        <add>All structure related aspects of a code module cropped into new class CTXRawCodeModule (inherited by CTXCodeModule).</add>
        <add multiline="1">
            <row>Added support for maintaining multiple system configuration files: </row>
            <row/>
            <row>- Directory 'contexo/ctxcfg' added for pooling system config files.</row> 
            <row>- default.cfg added to 'contexo/ctxcfg' which is a migration of settings previously defined in 'ctx.cfg'. </row>
            <row>- Old ctx.cfg changed, now pointing to the default.cfg file in 'contexo/ctxcfg'. </row>
            <row/>
            <row>NOTE: Please refer to user guide section "System configuration" for more information.</row>
        </add>
        <add>Added commandline tool 'switchcfg.py' which is used to switch between multiple system configurations.</add>

        <mod>Verbose level adjusted for some existing output messages.</mod>
        <mod>Full path to resolved CDEF tools displayed on verbose level 3.</mod>
        <mod>Resulting environment displayed after switching to it on verbose level 4.</mod>
        <mod>Warnings (level 4) treated as errors by all standard MSVC build configurations.</mod>
        <mod>Added "#! /usr/bin/env python" in all commandline tools for easier linux/unix/mac usage.</mod>
        <mod>All commandline tools in 'contexo/system/acc' moved to 'contexo/system/cmdline' (acc dir removed).</mod>
        <mod>Some logic error checks added when parsing CDEF files.</mod>
        <mod>Code module oriented classes moved to new python module - 'ctx_cmod.py'.</mod>
        <mod>ctx.env not implicitly added to env file list user already have included it (full path only).</mod>
        <mod>Added checks for illegal BC title characters.</mod>
        <mod>Added warning when COMP files doesn't generated output binaries (verbose level 1).</mod>
        <mod>Added error abort when COMP files doesn't generated any output at all.</mod>
        <mod>'import' arrangement refactored in most core modules.</mod>

        <bugfix>Added SCB_DEBUG to implicit preprocessor symbols when BC option DEBUG_BUILD is set to yes.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Fixed problem with quoted paths containing spaces (mostly detected in xdepends cases).</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Fixed python calling style for linux compatibility.</bugfix>
        <bugfix>Path error problem when using RANLIB fixed (erronous concat of output library name).</bugfix>
        <bugfix>ENDIAN typo fixed in 'ctx_bc.py'.</bugfix>
    </changes>
    <known_issues>
        <entry>Environment switching malfunctions on linux (and presumably other unix style platforms). The system fails to accept modifications to python "os.environ['PATH']" contents.</entry>
        <entry>No logging functionality available in 'buildmod.py'</entry>
        <entry>Commandline tools lacking de facto style option conventions.</entry>
        <entry>No modification detection is performed (all sources rebuilt each time).</entry>
    </known_issues>
</release>

<release>
    <title>Contexo 0.9b</title>
    <version>0.9</version>
    <date>2006-12-11</date>

    <comments>
        <entry>Initial release.</entry>
    </comments>
    <changes>
    </changes>
    <known_issues>
    </known_issues>
</release>

</release_notes>